One S&P 500 stock went up from mid-October
to mid-July in every midterm cycle
since 1986. I'll show you how I found it,
and the other stocks I'd look at
for the next six to twelve months.
In my last video,
I showed how TradeWave determined that
the market is very bearish right now,
which is September 16th, and
30 days from now, mid-October,
it's going to be bullish.
What if we want to buy stocks for
the next six to twelve months?
Which ones So I am on
Dow 30 stocks right now.
We already determined that we
want to analyze 30 days from now,
so this is October 15th.
I am going to change my filter
over here to 180 to 364...
366 days, for example. Now let's take a
look at the patterns that just came up.
First of all, 15 opportunities were found,
based on the last 10
years with 90% success,
and 100% of the patterns
that were found are bullish.
I can always look at Sharpe ratio.
Walmart is the most consistent,
although it was down one year.
Or look at average profit: Apple.
Also, a longer term: it's 341
days, and the average gain is 28.44%.
But remember, this is all based
on the last 10 consecutive years.
If I click this PE plus 2,
now this is based on the last
10 midterm election years,
which would span around 40 years.
I'm going to select Apple based on that.
Now there's a different analysis.
Apple actually did quite well in '86.
It was up 232%,
then it was up 165%
in 1990.
How about recently?
It was up 25% in 2022.
Now let's go to the S&P 500.
So this is midterm election years,
six-to-twelve-month patterns.
I'd rather have it by
Sharpe ratio initially,
to see what's the most consistent pattern.
AMETEK.
Look at that.
It gained 28.85%
every midterm election year from 1986
through 2022.
40% in 2022.
28%
in 2018. And what's the date range?
It's from the 15th of October
until the 16th of July.
Very close to the 100-Year Pattern.
Now let's look at the trend chart to
see if we can time it even better.
Look at the pivot.
We want to look at the pivot when the
average down move ends and the sharp up
move starts, which is right there.
Look at that: the average
gain jumped to 31.3%.
41% in 2022, and 23% in 2018.
AMETEK
has been a very bullish stock
during midterm election years,
starting on the 10th of October.
I just selected average profit.
Oh, look at this: Hubbell.
In 1994,
this stock made a thousand percent.
Wow, that really screws up this analysis.
So I'm going to cut these three years
and just take a look at the last seven.
That's a little bit more
realistic: an average gain of 19%.
45% gain in 2022 for Hubbell.
It says an SR of 0.37.
That's a very low Sharpe ratio,
and the real reason for it is
this incredible inconsistency,
because there is this
massive outlier in 1994.
However, Sharpe ratios do jump
if I switch it to seven years.
Just look at the bottom. The
Sharpe ratio is now above one.
So based on the last seven years,
this is a lot more consistent.
In finance, they determine
your risk is lower if your expected
return has been consistent.
So as you can see, when it's
consistent, your Sharpe ratio goes up.
Usually I look for Sharpe ratios
above one, but if it's above two,
I prefer it a lot more.
Eaton Corporation, with
average profits of 23.8%.
It was up 24% in 2022,
and only 3% in 2018,
27%
in 2014.
You can see all of these opportunities.
These are longer term. How about
shorter-term opportunities?
Just 30 days,
starting in the middle of October.
As you can see, they are all long
opportunities, 30 days from there.
Franklin Resources is
better a little earlier.
So look at the average gain of 6.37%.
I'm going to move this back.
The average gain jumped to 10%
if you go to start date
to the 11th of October.
Other stocks, like Disney.
Disney: average profit of 6%, based
on the last 10 midterm election years.
Disney does well. And look at this:
Disney goes up to around here,
which is next August,
August 2027.
Then it starts a pretty sharp decline.
Disney does this. Disney has a bearish
time of the year, and
it's very consistent.
I have the analysis shown in
The 100-Year Pattern book.
Thermo Fisher Scientific.
This one starts a little earlier too.
Average gain of 7.15%.
100% profitable, average around 9.49%,
and it's only 33
days. So this is how I pick
stocks to trade or invest in.
Now, there are so many
other analyses we can do
here, which I'll have in other videos.
So this is how it's done.
Try this yourself at TradeWave.ai.
And for the full research behind
these patterns, check out my book,
The 100-Year Pattern.